Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Water Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning water companies operating in the North American West
1879-1936
Ndy52
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(2 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning water companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, prospectuses, reports, maps, bondholders' agreements, letters to the stock- and bondholders, mortgage and trust indentures, plans for reorganization, and trust agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning water companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, prospectuses, reports, maps, bondholders' agreements, letters to the stock- and bondholders, mortgage and trust indentures, plans for reorganization, and trust agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Water utilities -- West (U.S.); Trust indentures -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Animas Power and Water Company, 1908; Ndy52 U2 +An54; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arkansas Electric and Water Company, 1929; Ndy52 U2 +Ar48; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- California Water and Telephone Company, 1920-1936; Ndy52 U2 +C128; (5 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Included are documents from the Sweetwater Water Corporation.
  Includes a consumer leaflet on the water supply in case of an air raid.
- City Water Company of Sedalia, 1925; Ndy52 U2 +C485; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Denver Union Water Company, 1914; Ndy52 U2 +D43; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- East Bay Water Company, 1921-1924; Ndy52 U2 +Ea7; (2 documents)
  - 1 document (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1 document (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Independence Waterworks Company, 1924-1925; Ndy52 U2 +In2; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Joplin Water Works Company, 1927; Ndy52 U2 +J74; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Omaha Water Works, 1896-1907; Ndy52 U2 +Om15; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Peoples Water Company, 1915; Ndy52 U2 +P39; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Raton Waterworks Company of New Mexico, 1909; Ndy52 U2 +R18; (4 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- San Jose Water Works, 1926-1934; Ndy52 U2 +Sa53; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Spring Valley Water Company, 1879-1923; Ndy52 U2 +Sp84; (8 documents) (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Wichita Water Company, 1924; Ndy52 U2 +W63; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 8)